A Guide to the Charles Williams Switzer papers, 1881-1927
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Charles Williams Switzer papers, 1881-1927
The Library of Virginia
45118
1.8 cubic feet and 4 boxes
Charles Williams Switzer
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Purchased from Jerry Craig of Waynesboro, Virginia.
Biographical Information
Charles Williams Switzer was born 16 February 1854 in Botetourt County, Virginia, to George Washington Switzer (1813-1870) and Sarah Ann Finch Switzer (1813-1897). Switzer was surveyor for Botetourt County from 1889-1928. He married Mary Virginia Burger (1857-1946) and they had thirteen children. Switzer died 6 February 1928 in Botetourt County and was buried in New Zion Hill Cemetery.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1881-1927, of Charles Williams Switzer (1854-1928) of Botetourt County, Virginia, consisting of surveys, deeds, and plats for real property in Botetourt, Alleghany, Craig, and Rockbridge Counties; land warrants for land acquired in Botetourt County; accounts, receipts, judicial and legal papers, election tallies, drafts, poems, and advertisements.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
Series I: Letters, 1882-1918 and no date
Series II: Accounts and Receipts, 1881-1916 and no date
Series III: Judicial and Legal Papers
Series IV: Miscellaneous Papers
Series V: Land Warrants, 1883-1884
Series VI: Survey, Plats, and Notes
Contents List
- Series I: Letters, 1882-1918 and no date., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1)
  Letters, 1882-1918 and no date, of Charles W. Switzer regarding land surveys for individuals and businesses, land warrants, and Switzer's personal insurance. Also includes a letter, 13 July 1894, from Bettie V. Miller of Gaithersburg, Maryland, to her sister containing family news.
  - Letters, 1882-1894. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Letters, 1904-1909. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Letters, 1910-1918, no date. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Series II: Accounts and Receipts, 1881-1916 and no date., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1)
  Accounts and Receipts, 1881-1916 and no date, of Switzer containing accounts and receipts for his work as a surveyor and of Switzer and his wife for personal items.
  - Accounts, professional and personal, 1889-1916, no date. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Receipts, 1881-1914, no date. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Series III: Judicial and Legal Papers., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1)
  Judicial and Legal Papers containing assignments, notices, board of supervisors paper, ejectments, chancery suits, lists, memorandums, oaths, settlements, summonses, attorneys' instructions, wills, and other papers concerning lands in legal matters and disputes, including the establishment of a free ferry.
  - Assignments. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Botetourt County government. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Ejectments and chancery suits. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Wills. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Attorneys' instructions. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous papers. (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Series IV: Miscellaneous Papers., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1)
  Miscellaneous Papers contain election tallies, bank draft, poem, and advertisements for stock and an ice cream parlor.
  - Election tallies. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous papers. (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Series V: Land Warrants, 1883-1884., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1)
  Land Warrants, 1883-1884, for 30 acres each. Portions of the 30 acres were claimed in Botetourt County.
  - Land warrants, 1883-1884. (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Series VI: Surveys, Plats, and Notes., Extent: 4 boxes. (Box 1-4)
  Surveys, Plats, and Notes for land in Botetourt, Alleghany, Craig, and Rockbridge Counties. Surveys are arranged alphabetically by last name for individuals and alphabetically by name for companies. Includes notes copied by Switzer for surveys dating back into the eighteenth century. Also contains survey lines for Botetourt County with Alleghany, Craig, and Roanoke Counties.
  - Ad-Ar. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Austin. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Ba. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Be. (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Beale. (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Bo. (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Br. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Bu. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Buchanan. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Buhrmann. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Ca. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Caldwell. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Ch-Co. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Cr-Cu. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Crush. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Da-Do. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Deisher. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Duffy. (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - E. (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - F. (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - G. (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Ha. (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Hannah. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - He-Hi. (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Ho-Hu. (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Papers filed as Hoffman vs. Harvey. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - J. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Ka-Ke. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Ki-Ky. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - L. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Ma. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Mc. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Me-Mu. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - N. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - O. (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - P. (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Poage. (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Price. (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - R. (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Reed/Reid. (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Sa-Sh. (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Si. (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Sl-Sp. (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - St-Sw. (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - T. (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - U. (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Wa-Wh. (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Wi-Wr. (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Y-Z. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Multiple names (folder 1 of 3). (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Multiple names (folder 2 of 3). (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Multiple names (folder 3 of 3). (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Multiple survey notes for named individuals (folder 1 of 3). (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Multiple survey notes for named individuals (folder 2 of 3). (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Multiple survey notes for named individuals (folder 3 of 3). (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Businesses. (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Joseph R. Anderson and Company. (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Tredegar. (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Locales. (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Unidentified (folder 1 of 3). (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Unidentified (folder 2 of 3). (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Unidentified (folder 3 of 3). (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Botetourt County boundaries. (Box 4, Folder 19)